[theme music playing]
[Jepoy] Julio Ardiente's in the hospital.
He had a heart attack.
Well, doctors found something different.
Grandpa was strangled.
That's outrageous.
Your dad would never do that
to your grandfather.
[Diego] What do you want from my family?
Ever since you arrived,
bad things started happening.
[Ivy] Stop the car.
[Diego] Even if you won't
answer my question,
I'll find out
who you really are, Miss Aguas.
You shouldn't get dragged
into this, Diego.
But if you get in my way,
I have no choice
but to deal with you, too.
[Raul] Why did you cover up for me?
[Emilia] I will keep everything
a secret, if you do what I want.
[Raul] You know what, Emilia?
If you think you can keep me
on a leash, then you're wrong.
[Emilia] On the contrary,
I don't want you here.
You can stay with your relatives,
if you still have any.
[Raul] Love, I'm back.
[Emilia] I am now
the matriarch of this family.
My time has come.
Now that the king is gone,
I shall reign as queen.
I will not push through with my investment
if it will inconvenience the farmers.
Why is this so personal to you?
Is there something you want to reveal?
Like skeletons in the closet?
[Raul] They may have killed Camia,
but I brought you back as Jasmin.
We'll use that against
the Ardientes someday.
[Arnaldo] You're running
for the Senate? But I'm the one
Grandpa's been grooming
to someday take his place.
Someday your time will come.
But now, it is my time.
[Belen] You need to tell the truth.
If Emilia finds out
you're keeping a woman here,
she won't just have your head,
she'll have Jasmin's, too.
Excuse me, ma'am.
[Emilia] Hmm. Can I see the back?
Bring it there.
Good morning, Madam Governor.
My name is Lara.
I'm a member of the staff
of Congressman Julio Ardiente.
I will be your executive assistant
while the Congressman is recovering.
I have my own executive
assistant at my office.
But this is different, Madam.
Since Congressman is unavailable,
you'll be attending events
and managing his projects.
And as your E.A, I will be providing you
with the timetables and schedules.
Fine.
Can you look for my husband?
A queen can't show up
without her king now, can she?
No, Governor.
You seem skilled and efficient,
so you better do your job now.
Go.
I said go.
[siren wailing]
-[cop] Get out! Get out! Quick!
-[people clamoring]
[cop] Move aside!
-Hurry up!
-The cops are here. Move it!
-Put them all here.
-Hurry up. The cops are here.
Gregorio Orallo, you are under arrest
for running a gambling den
in Poblacion Ardiente.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be used against you.
[cop] Over there! Over there!
Orallo. How many times
do I have to ask you?
All I need is just your cooperation.
But Governor…
I do everything you and Raul
tell me to do.
I can't go to jail. What about my family?
My daughter is still young, Madam.
[chuckles]
She really is.
And she is just so cute.
Madam Governor, I'm begging you.
Sir, please help me.
Orallo, if you still want
to see your daughter…
then do as I say.
So, will you take the fall for us…
or should I blow
your daughter's brains out?
-Take him in.
-Watch your head. Move it.
[reporter on TV]
After Gregorio Orallo cleared
the names of Gov. Emilia Ardiente-Torillo,
her husband Raul Torillo,
and Sen. Pablo Alcantara
from the gambling scandal,
he admitted he was Poblacion Ardiente's
resident gambling lord.
He was later found dead in his cell
in the evening after his arrest.
According to the police,
there was no foul play,
and Orallo committed suicide.
Here is Gov. Ardiente-Torillo's statement.
[Emilia] What happened today
was unfortunate.
But if there's one good thing about this,
it's that the gambling operations
that continue to tarnish the name
and image of Poblacion Ardiente,
has come to an end.
As the governor and mother of our town,
I promise to continue getting
rid of the evil in our town.
-What did you find?
-This.
So the Ardientes promised
to give the land to the farmers.
But they weren't able to transfer it
under the farmers' name.
The farmers never thought the Ardientes
would take it back, but they did.
Listen to me, Ivy.
You don't have to do anything.
I can gather evidence by myself.
Just leave everything to me.
I don't want you
putting yourself in danger.
-I can take care of myself.
-I know that. I do.
But don't you see how evil Emilia is?
You saw the news.
She had that man killed.
They're willing to take anyone
down just to clear their name.
So don't mingle with those devils.
How will I get justice for my family…
if I act like a coward?
[tense music playing]
Madrigal, are you done with
the errands I told you to run?
Yes, Mayor.
[Arnaldo] Ms. Aguas.
-Mr. Mayor.
-Congratulations.
The Governor's launching the project.
Well, thanks to you.
You're the one who convinced me to invest,
and stay here in Ardiente.
-Cheers.
-Babe! I missed you.
-Hey.
Oh. [chuckles]
Miss Aguas.
Hello.
How are you?
Enjoying the view.
And of course, enjoying
my new partnership with Arnaldo.
[Natalie laughs]
You know, Arnaldo really knows
how to use opportunities to his advantage.
Like that barren land.
Those farmers there are like leeches
sucking the nutrients from
a land that isn't even theirs.
And like your coming here.
There's this new girl in town,
and suddenly, there's a partnership!
[Natalie laughs]
Arnaldo, this means
that Natalie is really happy
that I invested here in Ardiente.
[laughs]
Ivy, don't get ahead of yourself.
I'm just saying that I'm happy.
And I'll stay happy if you stay here
strictly because of business.
And what if I don't?
No worries, Natalie.
I never mix business with pleasure.
Do you understand?
[laughs]
Oh, you're so cute.
I'm thirsty.
Can you get me a glass of wine?
Yeah. Sure.
Or better yet, I'll go with you. Let's go.
Okay.
[Natalie giggles]
[Natalie] Smile, baby.
Hey.
I didn't know all of Mom's
supporters would be here.
Even that Ivy Aguas.
Dad, I'll be off now.
Hold on. Where are you going?
We still have to--
I don't want to hear anything
about the EPZ.
Listen, Diego.
You're an Ardiente,
that's why you're here.
Sometimes, you have to do
things you don't want to.
That's one of the consequences
of being part of this family.
Sorry, Dad.
What took you so long?
The reception was terrible
at the place I was.
And where was that? Timbuktu?
Let's go.
-[Emilia] Hi, friends!
-[applause]
-[Emilia] Hello! Ivy. Hi!
You're so happy right now,
Emilia. Enjoy it while it lasts.
[Filipino folk music playing]
[applause]
Thank you very much,
Folklorico Dance Company.
Let's not beat around the bush.
Here is our beloved governor,
Governor Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
[applause]
A pleasant evening to everyone!
My friends!
I don't know where to start.
I'm sure everyone here knows about
our dear Congressman Julio
Ardiente's condition.
[Emilia sobs]
It's okay. It's okay.
[applause]
I'm very thankful for
my husband, Mr. Raul Torillo.
My father is currently in the U.S.
to recover and is accompanied
by his trusted aide.
But this is the proper moment
for all of us to unite
for Poblacion Ardiente
and for Señor Julio Ardiente!
[applause]
[Emilia] You know what they say.
While there's life,
there's hope and happiness.
Because I am still here
as your mother and governor of this town.
And I want you to call me Mommy Emilia…
the mother of this town!
[applause]
And for my first ever project
as mother of this town,
let me introduce to you
a good friend of mine.
I took her on as a consultant
for my EPZ project.
I wish to introduce to you,
Miss Ivy Aguas!
[applause]
Ivy, come join me.
Thank you.
Ivy.
[both chuckle]
Governor Emilia.
You know, our governor
here loves surprises.
Don't we all love surprises, Ivy?
It's better than being surprised.
I might have a heart attack like Papa.
[laughs]
You know, at least now,
your plans will push through.
Our plans.
You're not alone, Governor. You're right.
I should let go of my cheap sentiments,
so I can get what I want.
So, is it a yes?
Yes.
Great! Great!
Two women uniting for a cause.
Ivy, for… for Señor Julio!
For Poblacion Ardiente.
[applause]
Senator.
-Hi. Excuse me.
-Sure.
Emilia.
Fancy seeing you here, Senator.
Congratulations, Emilia.
I'm hoping for the success
of your leadership of this town
while Julio is recovering.
Thank you, Senator.
I hope you really mean that.
'Cause it would mean so much to me.
Of course, Emilia.
What's the purpose
of the long-standing friendship
between our families if not for that?
I know.
Our families have been friends
for the longest time.
And I do believe
that you find your true friends
in times of crisis, Senator.
I couldn't agree more.
Thank you.
-Senator Pablo.
-Miss Aguas.
Senator, I'll leave you with Miss Aguas.
-Excuse me.
-Thank you, Emilia.
-Madam, the press is waiting.
-Okay.
[Ivy] Senator.
Good evening. Good evening.
Is it true that you'll be
running for senator
in your father's place?
I'm just proving that
the people of Poblacion Ardiente
have nothing to fear
in my father's temporary absence,
because I am capable of taking over.
I am the mother of this town,
so I will make sure our town is safe.
-[applause]
-Thank you.
I see that you're still siding
with the Ardientes, Senator.
What was that you said at the party?
Politics is about making
friends, finding your allies,
and destroying your enemies.
Well, look at you,
you're Emilia's consultant now.
We politicians know that game well.
I am still Emilia's ally,
and we will clean up this mess.
But you, I wonder.
What's your game, Miss Aguas?
If I tell you, you might not
want to play anymore, Senator.
[tense music playing]
-[Loring] There.
-Miss Loring.
[Loring] Oh, thank you.
Miss Loring.
Oh, Miss Ivy, it's you!
Do you still have banana fritters?
Can I buy some?
Yes, ma'am.
Do you really want to buy them?
Yes. I'll buy all of them.
That's a lot. Aren't you on a diet?
-Not anymore.
-[Diego] Nanny, let's go.
I'll drive you to town.
[Loring] Ah…
Don't worry about the change.
It's an advance for next time.
-But…
-Just keep it for now.
-Miss Aguas.
Mr. Torillo.
Let me just get a bag for this.
I'll be quick.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, too.
Congratulations, by the way.
You were chosen as one
of Mama's consultants,
and your project is pushing through.
The last time we spoke,
didn't you tell me you'd stop?
Well, Mr. Torillo, as a businesswoman…
I studied the proposal carefully.
And I realized that the EPZ will
greatly benefit the farmers,
and all of Poblacion Ardiente.
You're oblivious, Miss Aguas.
That's the problem with people like you.
You see the poor as ants.
You think that their lives
will instantly change,
at the snap of your fingers.
Mr. Torillo, you're oblivious, too.
Miss Ivy, here are your fritters.
-Thank you, Miss Loring.
-For the rest of them--
-I'll get them next time.
-Okay. Thank you!
Senator, thank you for
helping us clear our name.
I'm just giving back the favor.
Thank you for the trust, Emilia.
Um, Senator, since our name
has been cleared of all issues,
maybe you can promote me in our party
as a replacement candidate
for Papa's senatorial bid.
[scoffs]
I knew it. Your friendship
comes with a price.
Seriously? You want to run for the Senate?
Senator, you're one of the most
influential people in the party.
Maybe you can vouch for me?
It's too early to tell.
Besides, the party
highly respects the opinions
of Senator Magno and Senator Jose.
They're the ones with the final say.
I see. Natalie, you should eat.
Yeah.
[grunting]
[Diego] You're oblivious, Ms. Aguas.
That's the problem with people like you.
You see the poor as ants.
You think that their lives will change
at the snap of your fingers.
[Ivy] Mr. Torillo, you're oblivious, too.
[grunting]
[grunts]
[shouts]
That woman just won't give in.
She's the reason
you're going to lose your land.
What should we do now?
Are we just going to sit here
while they take our land from us?
[shouts]
If I could just tell them
what I'm going through.
If only I could tell them
how evil the Ardientes are…
and about everything
they did to me and my family.
I'd shout it out!
I want everyone to know, especially Diego,
that I'm not just a rich businesswoman!
I'm a victim of his family, too.
[Ramon] Why are you always
blaming the Ardientes?
And you, Diego,
why are you always
going against your family?
Aren't you an Ardiente, too?
Mister Ramon, I don't want
to go against them.
I just can't accept
that my family pushed through
with the EPZ
all because of that Ivy Aguas!
I want to tell Diego
the truth that it's me.
I'm Lily, I'm your friend.
But of course, I can't do that.
This is her fault. And now what?
She tricked us all by giving
the go signal for the project.
We have to fight back.
[Carlotta] If this is weighing
you down, just remember
whom you're doing this for.
Nanny, I know that.
And I'll never forget that.
Tomorrow, I'll go to Emilia.
And I will make her feel
that Ivy Aguas is still her trusted ally.
[ominous music playing]
-[birds chirping]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[man] Turn left, go straight ahead,
and you'll see the governor's office.
[Ivy] Thank you.
Jasmin, I'll be going
to the market real quick.
Stay here--
Jasmin?
Jasmin!
Where'd she go? Jasmin?! Jasmin?!
My goodness. Where'd she go?
Jasmin?!
It's a good thing you were able
to clear my name from that scandal.
Don't flatter yourself, Raul.
You're part of this family,
so I was obligated to help you.
And always remember
that I'm the reason
you aren't rotting in jail.
I have you on a tight leash.
Jasmin?!
Where are you, Jasmin?!
[bleak instrumental playing]
[Belen sighs]
[phone ringing]
I need to take this call.
Hello, Auntie? Why did you call?
Raul, it's Jasmin…
Why? What happened to Jasmin?
She's gone. I've searched
the whole house for her.
Auntie, didn't I say to keep
an eye on her at all times?
You can't leave her by herself.
Auntie? Hello? Hello?
[tense music playing]
Where could she be? Jasmin!
Jasmin!
Oh, no! Oh, my! Look at you!
What are you doing?
I almost had a heart attack!
Let me see! Oh, my goodness!
Come, let's go home!
Be careful!
Let's go! Goodness.
-[phone ringing]
-Wait a second.
Hello. Raul.
Hello, Auntie? What happened?
Have you found her?
Yes, she's with me.
She almost fell off a cliff.
But don't worry, she's safe now.
How did she end up near a cliff?
Auntie, I entrusted her to you.
Please be more careful next time.
Okay, okay. Never mind.
I'll find a way to head
back there as soon as possible.
[Belen] All right. We'll wait for you.
Hi, Mr. Torillo.
You look… tense.
Miss Aguas. Have you been there long?
Yes. What about you?
Do you have an appointment somewhere?
From the tone of your voice,
it sounds like an emergency.
It's nothing. It's just…
it's just that some of my men
are stealing from me.
I asked my aunt to watch over them.
They're being such a nuisance.
It's difficult to trust them.
So you better be careful.
Ivy? Oh, Raul.
Emilia.
What are you doing here?
Um. I was just asking Mr. Torillo
where your office was, but here it is.
So, let's go?
Okay. Raul, let's go.
I just want to be certain
the land will be strategic
for our purposes.
Maybe I should visit the site.
Emilia?
Emilia, did you hear what I just said?
Oh. Yes. Do what you think is right.
I trust your judgment.
But please do it ASAP, okay?
Don't worry, Emilia.
I always make sure that
I finish everything I start.
Good.
-I have to go.
-Okay.
-Bye, Ivy.
-Bye.
I'll take you there.
-Mr. Torillo.
-Yeah.
Bye.
Where are you going?
I'm going out. I have errands--
Whoever you were talking to can wait. Sit.
I'm leaving.
[tense music playing]
Let's see if you can
still hide from me, Raul.
If you think you can fool me
again, then you're mistaken.
Not this time.
Miss Aguas.
Mr. Mayor, what are you doing here?
Well, I heard you were coming
here, so I decided to drop by.
Aside from the fact
that I always want to see you,
I brought something with me.
In less than a month, we can get
these farmers out of here.
Isn't that great news? Let's go.
Hey, man. Just one rooster today?
Yes, sir. It's the best cock
we have here, sir.
-All right.
-That's a sure winner, sir.
I'll just come back for it
next time, all right?
I came by unannounced, so…
Good morning, Governor.
Good morning.
All right, man. I'll call you again.
What are you doing here?
Raul, who's the woman
you've been coming here for?
Where is she? Bring her out.
What are you talking about, Emilia?
Raul, don't try to deny it.
Where is your other woman?
Where is she? Where is Ivy?
What the-- What woman
are you talking about?
Emilia, why don't you go see a doctor?
Because it sounds like you've gone nuts.
I'm here for the roosters
I was telling you about
for my cockfighting business.
That's why I'm here.
Didn't you see I was talking to a man?
Raul, don't try to act dumb.
Did you think I wouldn't notice
how you and Ivy were talking?
Your son likes her.
I'm not interested in that woman.
What if he didn't? You'd make a move then?
[scoffs]
Whatever, you're impossible.
Raul.
Just bring out your other woman.
I know she exists.
Where did you go when I kicked you out?
And who were you talking to on the phone?
No one.
So, you still don't know
what I'm capable of.
Do you know that I can finish you off
and have your woman
buried six feet under with you?
Try to leave.
You'll see what I can really do.
-[man] Hi, Mayor.
-[woman] Good morning.
[Arnaldo] Good morning.
[man 2] You're early today, Mayor.
I know. I just wanted to drop by.
These vegetables look delicious.
[woman] Yes. Our crops are always fresh.
I'm glad you had time for this.
I thought you had a lot of engagements.
I blocked them all off to be with you.
Mr. Mayor, about the eviction notice…
Isn't the time frame
you gave them too short?
Where do you plan
to relocate these people?
What about their livelihoods?
Ms. Aguas, everything's been planned out.
Don't worry.
Let's go?
How is the Congressman's health?
I just spoke to Papa's doctor, Senator.
He still needs to recover.
And I don't think he can handle
the stress of the campaign.
So, goodbye Julio for senator.
That's too bad.
Arnaldo has the leadership capability
and the whole package,
but he still has a lot to learn.
We need someone more
experienced to run for senator.
[clears throat]
One who knows the game well,
has the authority, has a good image,
and most importantly,
one who can definitely get people's votes.
Why not Emilia?
Well, senators, I've been
serving my constituents
for the past 10 years.
And in the game of politics, I always win.
[Magno] Yes, that's true.
But, no offense Emilia…
there are things about your credentials,
which we find lacking.
Your father is a known
politician on a national scale.
If you can't reach
Julio's level of influence,
by the time the campaign period starts,
you'll only be wasting time and money.
Because you'll surely lose.
[tense music playing]
-[woman] There you go.
-[man] The mayor's here!
[man 2] Oh. It's the mayor. The mayor.
[woman 2] The mayor.
[Loring] Oh. Wait, wait. Careful.
[woman] You dropped the eggplants.
[Fernan] Mayor, Miss Ivy…
-[man 3] Good afternoon.
-What brings you…
-to our place?
-[man 4] Good afternoon.
[Nimfa] Hi, Mayor Arnaldo!
You're so handsome, just like Diego.
Ah… I guess it runs in the family.
Hey, your father
is handsome, too! See that?
Of course, Dad.
And me, too, right?
-Of course, Butchoy.
-[Ramon] Hold on.
Why do we have two
lovely ladies with us today?
Nimfa and Miss Ivy.
Thank you.
Miss Ivy is prettier, Mr. Ramon.
Plus, she's rich and intelligent.
You're beautiful, too, Nimfa.
But thank you.
Mr. Mayor, you should be proud.
The people of Ardiente
aren't just hardworking,
they're good people.
Ah… Mr. Fernan.
That sounded so genuine.
I just wish you were sincere about that.
Come again, Miss Loring?
It's so hot today.
Gosh. Good thing it's breezy!
[Loring and Nimfa chuckle]
Lara, can I talk to Mom?
Sorry, sir.
You don't have an appointment
with the governor.
Why don't you wait for her
to come home, instead?
Lara, please. She needs to read this.
If she doesn't, the farmers
might lose their livelihood.
You understand that, right?
Wait here, sir.
I think Emilia still has time to catch up
with Julio's popularity.
Excuse me, Madam Governor.
I'm really very sorry to interrupt,
but someone's looking for you.
-Who is it?
-It's Diego.
Can you please tell him
I'm in the middle of a meeting?
We'll just talk at home.
-Yes, Madam.
-Let him in.
Anyway, we're done here, Emilia.
We'll talk some other time.
-Thank you, Senator Jose.
-You're welcome.
Senator Magno.
[tense music playing]
Excuse us for a bit.
We'll just get you something to drink.
-[Nimfa] Oh.
-Thank you.
-I'm coming with you.
-Let's go.
Come on.
-Miss Loring.
-Yes?
[chuckles softly]
I still have a chance with Diego, right?
Of course.
Don't worry about that.
Diego really doesn't like her.
-[Nimfa] I knew it.
-[Loring] Yeah.
[Loring] She doesn't like him, either.
Wait. Do you think I'm his type?
Did I say you weren't?
No, I didn't. I didn't say that.
Forget about that. Don't worry.
You have a good chance.
Let's just say that Miss Ivy
just has nice makeup on.
-[both chuckling]
-I knew it!
-Miss Loring, Nimfa.
-Yes?
Can you tell me what's so funny?
It's nothing, Ms. Ivy.
Um. Why are you here, anyway?
You and the mayor.
-[Arnaldo] Friends!
-Oh.
Can you please come closer?
I'd like to say a few words.
[Loring] Here we go.
Well, we're here because…
And I've said this before.
We're planning to put up
an export processing zone
here in Poblacion Ardiente.
So, I'm here as your mayor,
and Ivy's here as the
consultant for the project
to ask for your support.
You all need to vacate this property.
-What?!
-What?
[townsfolk murmuring indistinctly]
You know, this is useless!
We've already issued an eviction notice!
Mom, hear them out first.
The two of you have given me
nothing but problems.
You always leave to see your mistress.
And you. Why can't you wrap your head
around the idea that we don't
owe anything to those farmers?
You are an Ardiente,
that's why you don't have
to side with them on this issue!
No, Mom. If you'd only hear them out,
you'd understand
what you're doing is wrong.
Mayor…
I don't think this is right.
What about our livelihood?
We can't just leave this place.
-She's right.
-We won't allow this.
[crowd murmuring indistinctly]
Mr. Pandoy, Miss Loring.
Based on this document,
we've given you a lot of time to move out.
But don't worry.
We'll relocate you elsewhere.
You just have to leave
as soon as possible.
Hold on, sir.
But you're not telling us
where you'll relocate us.
We don't even know if we can start anew.
Are you telling us to leave,
Mayor and Miss Beautiful?
Please don't make us leave.
We'll lose our homes again.
We won't have anywhere to go.
What else can't you understand?!
You're wasting my time. Leave.
-Mom.
-Leave!
[tense music playing]
[gasps]
[groans]
[grunts]
[tense music playing]
-[Arnaldo] Careful.
-[people exclaim]
[Arnaldo] I didn't like
what you did earlier.
[Diego] If you always got
what you wanted back then,
it won't happen this time.
Ivy doesn't like you.
[Ivy] You've been best friends
since you were kids?
[Loring] Diego had only one best friend.
And she was his one and only true love.
Her name is Lily.
I have here an old draft,
the deed of donation
confirming that the land
was donated to the farmers.
[Arnaldo] You're different.
Perfect characteristics
of a first lady. My first lady.
[Diego] Miss Aguas, wait.
[theme music playing]